A Guide to the Edward N. Eubank Papers, 1877-1932
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Edward N. Eubank Papers, 1877-1932
The Library of Virginia
51218
.45 cubic feet (1 box)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the State Records Section, The Library of Virginia, Richmond.
Biographical Information
Edward N. Eubank was born 17 July 1853 in Lynchburg, Virginia. He spent some years as a reporter for a Lynchburg newspapers before moving to Newport News, Virginia, in 1896. After moving to Newport News, Eubank worked for the Chesapeake and Ohio Railroad and for the United States customs service, retiring from that position in 1929. Eubank was a member of the Virginia national guard retiring with the rank of captain in 1925, and was promoted to major under legislation enacted by Governor Harry F. Byrd. Eubank was active in the masons, serving as grand master for Virginia in 1902 and 1903. He was a historian of both Virginia and military history. Eubank died in Newport News 14 January 1946 and was buried in Spring Hill Cemetery in Lynchburg.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1877-1932, of Edward N. Eubank (1853-1946) of Newport News, Virginia, relating to his involvement in the Virginia Volunteers, including a clothing account book of the Lynchburg Home Guard, accounts, receipts, and an officers' roster of the Huntington Rifles, manuals on the use and regulations of small arms and rifles, and legislation in the Virginia General Assembly concerning the retirement of officers. The collection also contains Eubank's notes on the organization of Confederate units from Alabama, and numerous publications.
Contents List
- Alabama Infantry Regiments, 1st-61st. (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
- Alabama Cavalry. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Alabama State Reserves. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Alabama Miscellaneous Units. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Army and Navy Register, June 1928. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Book of the Month Club. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Chesapeake and Ohio Railway Schedule, 1928. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Clipping - 319th Infantry. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Code of Virginia - Public Defense. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- The Diocesan Record of Southern Virginia, June 1928. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Educational News, May-June 1928. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- First National Bank. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Huntington Rifles - Accounts and Receipts, 1905-1907. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Huntington Rifles - Roster of Officers. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Invitation - 323rd Field Signal Battalion, 1928. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- List of Teachers - Newport News, 1916. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Literary Digest, 26 May 1928. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Lynchburg Home Guard - Clothing Account Book, 1877. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Poem. (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Retirement of Officers. (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Rifle Practice Arranged for the Beginner. (Box 1, Folder 24)
- The Rockbridge Mason, June 1928. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Small Arms Firing Regulations. (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Uniforms. (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Use of Rifles. (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Virginia Guardsman, 1931-1932. (Box 1, Folder 29)